### Contact

thakersamveg608@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/samveg-thaker (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Android Development Android Android SDK

### Languages

English (Professional Working) Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Learning ASP.NET Core MVC
Building and Securing RESTful APIs
in ASP.NET Core

Smart India Hackathon 2019 Winner Visual Studio Essential Training: 09 Unit Tests

Azure: Understanding the Big Picture

# Samveg Thaker

Trying to save student lives | SIH 2019 Winner | Ex-DSC Lead | Developer

Raipur

# Summary

A B-Tech graduate, who started a company in 2nd year, trying to help other startups in digitalization. Finally in the final year, thought of shifting from service-based to product-based startup and now helping colleges in saving precious student lives. Also, working as a Software Engineer at Microsoft helping the developers by improving their development experience.

## Experience

Microsoft Software Engineer July 2020 - Present (2 months) Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Zenithec Techware Co-Founder and CEO March 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Raipur, Chattisgarh, India

Started and lead the development of a website of CA JK Gupta( https://jkgupta.in/) and an admin panel for him.

Lead a team of 4 for developing a Resume Builder platform called Boosted( https://www.boosted.in/ ). Successful development and deployment in Production and staging server.

Lead a team of 4 experienced Android and iOS developers, a backend engineer and graphic designer for the successful launch of PetBro( https://www.petbro.in/) one of its kind Pet Care applications.

Microsoft Software Engineer Intern May 2019 - July 2019 (3 months) Hyderabad, Telangana, India I worked in the Azure DevOps Search team. Improved the code search by implementing Machine Learning based code search. Learned Natural Language Processing, Python and Flask as the part of my project. Implemented Skip-Gram model, Tf-Idf Vectorization and much more.

Perrault Health Intern May 2018 - July 2018 (3 months) Gurgaon, India

Android Development Internship. Developed an Android application for health purposes. Used for maintaining prescriptions, ordering medicines, getting lab tests done and check availability of doctor and appointment booking.

I developed pharmacy and doctor listing. Search for medicine and integrated PayTm payment gateway.

NcflexE, IIT Kanpur Software Developer Internship March 2018 - April 2018 (2 months) Kanpur Area, India

Contributed in one of a kind application by TransPacks Technology. Worked on auto update feature for the application in the brief 1-month internship.

## Education

National Institute of Technology Raipur
Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science · (2016 - 2020)